VLADIMIR IVANOV

 $^{(2)}$ +7 (924) 320·09·34 | \bowtie person@v-u-ivanov.com Vladivostok, Maritime Province, Russia

SUMMARY

Practical engineer with a focus on the EECS. 3+ years of experience in designing of embedded systems. I have built own experience through hardware and software co-design. Strong skills in electrical engineering, computer science and research area. Looking for new career opportunities in a team of professionals with using of progressive technologies and tools. Main areas of interest are consumer electronics, robotics, automotive and game industry, medical equipment, telecommunication and networks. No blocking problems to work outside the current location.

EDUCATION

Far Eastern State University, Vladivostok

August 2005 – June 2010

M.S. Departments of General Physics and Electronics.

Degree work was defended in the underwater robotics area.

GPA: 3.63 out of 4.

Secondary school 51, Vladivostok

September 2003 – June 2005

Secondary education.

In-depth study of Japanese Language.

Secondary school 51, Vladivostok

September 1995 – June 2003

General education.

In-depth study of Japanese Language.

SERTIFICATES

- Two-month course "6.00.1x: Introduction to CS and Programming". Excellent passing grade. The online learning initiative of Harvard University and MIT, December 2013.
- Three-month course "6.002x: Circuits and Electronics". Maximum passing grade. The online learning initiative of Harvard University and MIT, June 2012.
- Course of Japanese Language. The course of 1150 hours and a number of final exams. Secondary school 51 of Vladivostok, 1995 2005.

PUBLICATIONS

• Ivanov V. "The diagnostic system of a motor drive module for a underwater robot". Master thesis. Institute of Marine Technology Problems FEB RAS, Vladivostok, June 2010.

EXPERIENCE

Rhonda Software Ltd.

October 2012 – present Vladivostok, RUS

Embedded Software Engineer

- · CSR plc. contractor, work on the COACH imaging SoC/DSP platform.
- \cdot Distributed supporting of the embedded software for ODM/OEM customers: main manufacturers of imaging devices (digital still cameras, mobile driver recorders, action cameras, etc).
- · Support offices are located in a number of countries: China, Israel, Japan, Russia, South Korea, US.
- · Supported peripheral domain: on-chip peripheral, optic sensors, solid state storages, displays, PC-side applied software, various peripheral-specific firmware algorithms.

- · Solving of time-critical project issues under a customer's pressure: resolved a number of various "MP block" software and hardware problems.
- · Designing and implementing of new requested features, rework of the API: improved processing performance of UI images for customer's projects.
- · Business trip to CSR Israel (former Zoran Corp.): MATAM, Advanced Technology Center, Haifa.

Spider Pacific Ltd.

October 2010 – October 2012

Embedded Systems Engineer

Vladivostok, RUS

- · Startup for a development of an applied hardware.
- · Designed maket of the mechanical-less manipulator as part of the project management software system.
- · Designed and manufactured prototype of the valve tubes amplifier for a PC sound cards.
- · Designed and manufactured "Power over Ethernet" injector. Implemented physical layer of the IEEE 802.3af standart. The product was used in a number of computer network projects.

SKILLS

Development	embedded C, C++, automation (Python and Perl), multithreading, interrupt- and event-driven design, device drivers, version control, code review, issue tracking, code documentation
Debugging	logs analyzing, in-circuit emulation, remote debugging, lab equipment usage
Electronics	digital/analog/tube circuits design, electrical (KCL, KVL, etc.) and thermal calculations, selection of electronic components, routing and assembling of prototype PCBs (hole-mount and SMD)
Languages	English (professional working proficiency) 日本語 (limited working proficiency) Russian (native)
Misc	foundations of project management, lathe and milling works, bring up of computer networks, a bit experience in transferring of knowledges to students

KEYWORDS

1-Wire, ADC, Atomthreads, AVR, Bash, BSP, C, C++, CAN, CCD/CMOS optic sensor, Code Collaborator, cross-compiler, Cygwin, DAC, device driver, Doxygen, Eagle CAD, Eclipse, eTraxis, FAT, FileX, Gerber, Git, GNU toolchain, G-Sensor, gyro sensor, HW/SW co-design, IEEE 802.3af, I2C, JIRA, JTAG, KiCAD, libpng, Linux, Maxima, MCS-51, MIPS, OOP, OSI, Perforce, Perl, PHP, PIC, Proxxon, Python, QuickBuild, R&D, Redmine, RS-232, RTOS, SPI, SPICE, Spider Project, RAW Bayer, Source Insight, SQL, SVN, TEX, ThreadX, UART, UML, V8, Visual Studio, Windows, zlib

HOBBY AND INTERESTS

- · Hi-Tech and impacting one on a human being, designing hardware and software
- · Physics (two completed university years), applied math, world economic
- · Professional sports leagues: NHL, NFL, MLB
- · Swimming (sports category), marine multiathlon (sports category)
- · Cooking, electronic music